hi everyone it's great to see you and
大家好，很高兴见到你和你
it's a privilege to have the last two
拥有最后两个是特权
sessions with you and I want to tell you
和你见面，我想告诉你
again as I tried to do the first two
再次，因为我试图做前两个
weekends I think you're a very special
周末我觉得你很特别
group of people to be willing to invest
这帮人要舍得投入
all this time and come listen to us
所有这些时间来听我们说
drone on and on so thank you for sitting
上和无人机所以谢谢你坐
here and enduring and these next two
在这里，忍受和接下来的两个
sessions are very near and dear to my
会议非常接近我亲爱的
heart for this reason and I want to
心因为这个原因而且我想
quickly introduce you to my family first
先把你介绍给我的家人
of all I don't have to introduce her
我没有必要介绍她
through a picture my wife is with me
通过照片， 我的妻子和我在一起
today so Rose is right over here
今天罗斯就在这里
and my motivation for showing you the
和我向你展示你的动机
picture other than to brag on my family
除了吹嘘我的家人之外的照片
a little bit is to show you that or to
一点点就是告诉你那个或那个
demonstrate that the sessions that
表明会话的
you're about to hear are just not theory
你即将听到的只是没有理论
but they have been put to practice in
但是他们已经付诸实践了
the trenches of family life we have six
家庭生活的战壕我们有六个
children and three boys and three girls
孩子们和三个男孩和三个女孩
and so there's some extra ones up there
所以那里还有一些额外的
and you're in this first session in
而你在这第一次会议
particular you're going to be hearing
特别是你会听到
some of their testimonies because the
他们的一些见证是因为
way I've chosen to cover this topic of
我选择的方式来涵盖这个话题
family instruction or parental
家庭教育或父母
instruction is to talk about what I call
指令是谈论我称之为
the strategic nature of Family Worship a
家庭崇拜的战略性质a
family devotional time has been
家庭的奉献时间一直在
something that's been a tradition in our
这是我们的传统
family for decades now and we would say
家庭几十年了，我们会说
that it's one of the richest blessings
这是最丰富的祝福之一
that the Lord ever led us to pursue when
耶和华曾引导我们去追求
we first started parenting and I hope to
我们首先开始养育孩子，我希望
convince some of you of this over the
说服一些你的这个过
next hour as we talk about how do you as
下一个小时，我们谈谈你是怎么做的
parents instruct or how do you teach
父母指导或你如何教导
your counsel leaves to instruct their
你的律师离开去指导他们
children now let me clarify right off
孩子们现在让我澄清一下
the bat that you're not going to be
你不会去的蝙蝠
hearing me say that the Bible teaches
听我说圣经教导
that every family must have family
每个家庭都必须有家人
worship I think that would be legalistic
崇拜我认为这将是合法的
if I tried to find chapter and verse
如果我试图找到章和节
that said every family must have a
说每个家庭都必须有一个
family devotional time but Awana is not
家庭奉献时间，但Awana不是
in the Bible and we think it's a good
在圣经中我们认为这很好
idea right and Sunday school is not in
想法正确，周日学校不在
the Bible but we think it's a good idea
圣经， 但我们认为这是一个好主意
there are methodologies that we use that
有我们使用的方法
demonstrate biblical principles and
证明圣经的原则和
that's the category that I think this
这是我认为的类别
would fall into the biblical principle
会落入圣经的原则
would be this we are called to disciple
就是这个我们被称为门徒
our children and as arched as our family
我们的孩子和我们的家庭一样拱起
got larger and larger the idea of having
越来越大的想法
individual discipleship time really got
个人的门徒训练时间真的到了
out of the question of having individual
没有个人的问题
meetings with children weekly so the
每周与孩子们见面
methodology that we chose to pursue for
方法，我们选择了追求
disciple in our children because that is
因为那是我们孩子的弟子
the biblical principles we must disciple
我们必须遵守的圣经原则
our children and I just add a
我们的孩子和我只是添加一个
parenthesis here be disciple in your
这里的括号是你的弟子
children because if you're not somebody
孩子，因为如果你不是某个人
will and it's going to be the world
意志，它将成为世界
probably or their flesh is going to be
可能或他们的肉将会是
disciple
弟子
somebody will be disciple annealed Rijn
有人将门徒退火Rijn
and the methodology that we chose to do
以及我们选择做的方法
that is through regular family worship
这是通过定期的家庭崇拜
so what we're gonna do is go through of
所以我们要做的就是通过
what I call a theology of family worship
我称之为家庭崇拜的神学
not finding chapter and verse in the
没有找到章节和诗句
Bible of family worship but how can you
家庭崇拜的圣经， 但你怎么样
use this to fulfill the biblical
用它来实现圣经
principle of discipleship and then you
门徒训练的原则然后你
are going to hear from our children
我们要听听孩子们的意见
because I've had our kids right out
因为我让我们的孩子出去了
testimonies of what family worship has
家庭崇拜的见证
meant to them through the years so
这些年来对他们意味着什么
you're gonna hear from three of our kids
你会听到我们三个孩子的消息
as they talk about the significance of
当他们谈论的重要性时
family worship in their lives the first
家庭崇拜在他们的生活中第一
passage I'd like you to turn to a second
通过我想你把第二
Timothy chapter 3 and these are famous
蒂莫西第3章和这些都很有名
verses because of the last verses of the
经文，因为最后的经文
chapter that all Scripture is inspired
所有经文都受到启发的章节
by God and profitable for teaching for
由上帝和有益于教学
reproof for correction for training and
责备改正训练和训练
righteous
正义
this that the man of God may be adequate
这是神的人得以完全
equipped for every good work if you had
如果你有的话，为每一项好工作做好准备
a dollar for every time you've heard
你每次听到都要一块钱
that in the last three months you
在过去的三个月里你
probably could go out to eat at least at
可能至少可以出去吃饭
a pretty nice restaurant the amount of
一个相当不错的餐厅的数量
times you've heard that at BCD a in the
你曾经听说过BCD中的那个
last three months but I want to expand
过去三个月， 但我想扩大
this into the context of the chapter a
这进入了章节的背景
little bit and just walk you through the
一点点， 只是带你走过
chapter and show you how the Lord used
章节并告诉你主如何使用
this chapter to just really impress on
这一章真的让人印象深刻
my heart the necessity of leading our
我的心是领导我们的必要性
family and family worship and I'm really
家庭和家庭崇拜，我真的
glad he did we have so many wonderful
他很高兴我们有这么多精彩
memories from family worship it's one of
家庭崇拜的记忆是其中之一
our favorite things to do here's the
我们最喜欢做的事情就是这里
context so let's think about the context
上下文让我们考虑一下上下文
a little bit it's really one of the most
一点点这真是一个最
depressing chapters in the Bible when
在圣经中，当郁闷的章节
you read it it starts off bed and then
你读它它从床上开始然后
it gets worse so it starts off with
事情变得更糟糕，因此有开始了
realize this that in the last days
在最后的日子里意识到这一点
difficult times will come have you been
你会遇到困难时期
wondering whether we're in those days
想知道我们是否在那些日子里
look at the next verse men will be
看下一节男人会
lovers of self lovers of money boastful
自恋爱好者的爱好者自夸
arrogant revilers disobedient to parents
傲慢的反叛者不听父母的话
ungrateful unholy etc etc last phrase of
忘恩负义邪恶等等等等最后一句
verse 4 lovers of pleasure rather than
第4节爱好者而非爱人
lovers of God and you read those
上帝的爱人， 你读这些
descriptions and you go wow that sure
描述，你肯定哇哇
sounds like the United States of America
听起来像美利坚合众国
right now and that's depressing
现在，这令人沮丧
now look in the middle of the chapter it
现在看看章节的中间吧
really goes from bad to worse he says
他说，真的变得越来越糟糕
this verse 10 but you followed my
这节经文10，但你跟着我
teaching conduct purpose faith patience
教学行为目的是信心耐心
love perseverance persecutions
爱坚持不懈的迫害
sufferings such as happened to me at
像我这样的痛苦发生在
Antioch at Iconium at Lystra what
安提阿在Iconium在Lystra什么的
persecutions I endured and out of them
我忍受的迫害和他们的迫害
all the Lord delivered me and then this
所有的主都把我救然后这个
verse that we kind of wish wasn't in the
诗句， 我们有种想是不是在
New Testament indeed all who desire to
新约确实是所有渴望的人
live godly in Christ Jesus will be
在基督里生活敬虔耶稣会
persecuted and it gets even more
迫害，它变得更多
depressing right in the middle of the
在中间闷闷不乐
chapter and guess what
章和猜猜是什么
it's the picture gets bleaker look at
这张照片看起来更加黯淡
the next verse but evil
下一节但邪恶
and imposters will proceed from bad to
和冒名顶替者将从坏到 深
worse deceiving and being deceived he's
更糟糕的欺骗和欺骗他
talking about in the end times false
谈论到底是错误的
teaching and as I read the chapter what
教学和我读的章节是什么
I'm reading is cultural deterioration
我读的是文化恶化
culture is just deteriorating and boy
文化正在恶化和男孩
are we experiencing that now what are we
我们现在经历的是什么呢？
supposed to do in the midst of cultural
应该在文化中做
deterioration next verse
恶化下一节
you however Timothy in the midst of all
但是蒂莫西却在你们中间
this you Timothy continue in the things
这是蒂莫西继续做的事情
you've learned and become convinced of
你已经学会了并且深信不疑
knowing from whom you have learned them
知道你从谁那里学到了它们
so Timothy as you see your culture
蒂莫西，你看到你的文化
deteriorating around you as you see
如你所见，在你周围恶化
false teaching increasing what do you do
错误的教学增加你做什么
Timothy cling to scripture because all
提摩太 因为所有而 坚持圣经
Scripture is given by inspiration of God
圣经是上帝的启示
and is profitable for doctrine reproof
并且对于教条的责备是有利可图的
does that bring new meaning to those
这会给那些带来新的意义吗？
those verses the context of the chapter
这些经文是本章的背景
and then he says this knowing from whom
然后他说这知道是谁
you've learned them well in the book of
你已经在书中学到了很多
2nd Timothy who was he talking about
他正在谈论的第二个提摩太
chapter 1 verse 5 it's very easy to
第1章第5节是很容易
trace he's talking about his mother and
追踪他正在谈论他的母亲和
his grandmother Eunice and Lois who had
他的祖母Eunice和Lois曾经
this significant impact on Timothy
这对提摩太的影响很大
and then next verse that from childhood
然后是从童年开始的下一节经文
you've known the sacred writings which
你已经知道哪些神圣的着作
are able to give you the wisdom that
能够给你的智慧
leads to salvation through faith which
通过信仰导致救赎
is in Christ Jesus so here's the context
在基督耶稣里，所以这里是背景
it's a pattern of the Word of God being
这是上帝之道的模式
central in the home for dealing with the
在家中央处理
perplexities of life and his mother and
生活和他母亲的困惑
grandmother taught him that from the
奶奶教他这个
time that he was a child and that word
一次， 他还是个孩子，并且 字
child is a very significant word it's
孩子是一个非常重要的词
not the normal word for child and this
不是孩子和这个的正常词
is the first the one of the very first
是第一个第一个
steps that the Lord used to impress upon
主曾经给人留下深刻印象的步骤
me the necessity of training my children
我需要训练我的孩子
instructing my children and we chose the
指导我的孩子， 我们选择了
methodology of family worship is this
家庭崇拜的方法论就是这样
Greek word brief us it's the same as the
希腊语简介我们它和它一样
word when Mary
玛丽说的
went to visit her cousin Elizabeth and
去看望她的堂兄伊丽莎白和
they greeted each other and remember the
他们互相打招呼，记住了
story in Luke the baby leaped in
在路加的故事中，宝宝跳了进来
Elizabeth's womb John the Baptist leaped
伊丽莎白的子宫施洗约翰跳了起来
in Elizabeth's womb this is a preborn
在伊丽莎白的子宫里，这是一个先天
baby or a very young child and when I
宝贝还是一个非常小的孩子，当我
was translating that in seminary and we
正在翻译神学院和我们
were expecting our first child the Lord
期待我们的第一个孩子是主
just impressed upon me the necessity of
只是给我留下了必要的印象
starting from the time that the child is
从孩子的时间开始
very young and raising it in a home
非常年轻，并在家中提高它
where the atmosphere of the home is how
家里的气氛是怎样的
do you deal with the perplexities of
你处理的困惑
life you deal with them through biblical
你通过圣经与他们打交道的生活
principles and we determined that we
原则，我们决定我们
were gonna start family worship from
将要开始家庭崇拜
that time and we did let's keep building
那个时候我们确实让我们继续建设
our our theology of family worship and
我们的家庭崇拜和神学
I'd like you to go to a significant
我希望你能去一个重要的
passage of Scripture Ephesians chapter 6
经文以弗所书第6章
and in the next presentation this
并在接下来的演示上
passage is going to come up again when
通道将会再次出现
we talk about disciplining children
我们谈论训练孩子
Ephesians chapter 6 while you're turning
以弗所书第6章，当你转身时
there just so I make sure I fit in some
在那里我确保我适合一些
of these testimonies so you're gonna
这些见证所以你要去
hear from two of our sons and one of our
从我们的两个儿子和一个听到我们
daughters this is our son Joel he's now
女儿这是我们的儿子乔尔他现在
graduating from the Masters College Lord
从大师学院毕业勋爵
willing this spring and getting married
愿意今年春天结婚
graduating Friday night getting married
周五晚上毕业结婚
Saturday how do you like that he and his
星期六你怎么样他和他的
wife to be are praying about seminary at
妻子要在神学院祈祷
of course TMS and they he would like to
当然是TMS和他们想要的
introduce Israel to biblical counseling
向以色列介绍圣经辅导
that's his ambition right now and he
那是他现在的野心 和他
wrote this a few years ago family
几年前写过这个 家庭
devotions is a special time for me
对我来说，奉献是一个特殊的时刻
individually it's a time for me to just
个别是我的时间
sit and enjoy worshiping the creator of
坐下来享受崇拜的创造者
the universe and with my family in
宇宙和我的家人在
particular it's a time to enjoy
特别是享受的时间
fellowshipping with my family sitting
与我的家人坐在一起
and worshiping with my family is such an
和我的家人一起敬拜是这样的
awesome experience I can't even describe
很棒的经历，我甚至无法形容
it without family devotions growing up I
它没有家庭的灵魂成长我
would probably not be a Christian today
今天 可能不会是基督徒
it is through devotions as a family that
这是通过作为一个家庭的奉献
came to Christ and repented of my sin
来到基督面前，悔改了我的罪
after salvation devotions helped me to
救恩后的虔诚帮助了我
grow abundantly in my walk with God I
在我与神同行的过程中大量增长
thank God for the family I have and I'll
感谢上帝为我的家人而且我会
read you two more in just a little bit
只需一点点就能再读两遍
let's go to Ephesians chapter 6 and a
让我们去Ephesians第6章和a
very significant passage about fathers
关于父亲的非常重要的段落
fathers do not provoke your children to
父亲不会激怒你的孩子
anger but bring them up so that implies
愤怒， 但把它们带上来暗示
Direction bring them up more about that
方向让他们更多地了解这一点
in the next session in the discipline
在该学科的下一届会议上
and instruction of the Lord
并指示主
anytime Paul says in Ephesians like for
任何时候保罗在以弗所书中说过
example verse 1 children obey your
例如第1节儿童服从你的
parents in the Lord for he says of the
父亲在主里面，他说的是
Lord you have to keep it in the context
主啊，你必须把它放在上下文中
of Ephesians what's he talking about
以弗所书他在说什么
well who's the Lord in Ephesians in
以及以弗所书中的主是谁
Ephesians the Lord is obviously the Lord
主以弗所书显然是主
Jesus Christ and he's the head of his
耶稣和他的头上
body the church
身体教会
that's chapters 1 2 3 now chapters 4 to
那是第1章2 3章，现在是第4章到第4章
6 it's live like Christ is the head of
6 它的存在就像基督是其头
his body the church in your life that's
他的身体就是你生命中的 教会
why he says in chapter 4 verse 1 walk in
为什么他在第4章第1节说道
a manner worthy of the calling with
一种值得称呼的方式
which you've been called but what you're
你被称为但你是什么
calling Christ is your head and he's the
称基督是你的头，他就是你的头
head of his body the church
教堂的头部
so father's we want to bring up do not
所以我们想要提出的父亲不要
provoke your children to anger but bring
挑起你的孩子愤怒，但带来
them up in the discipline and
他们在学科和
instruction of the Lord the Lord who is
主耶和华的指示
the head of his body the church it's a
他的身体是教会的头部
home that is a gospel centered home a
家， 就是一个福音为中心的家
home where Christ is first we have this
在基督第一的地方，我们拥有这个
sign if you walk into our home and look
如果你走进我们的家，看看
on the mantle right as you walk in the
当你走进去的时候 ，在地幔上
door you look straight ahead above our
你直视我们的门
little fireplace you'd see a sign we've
小壁炉， 你会看到我们的标志
had for decades now that says home sweet
几十年来， 现在说家庭甜蜜
home when Christ is first and we don't
当基督是第一个而我们没有
want that just to be a cute saying we
我希望这只是一个可爱的说法
really want that to be the atmosphere of
真的希望那是大气的
our home a gospel saturated home so
我们家的福音饱和了所以
let's and I can trace that right through
让我和我可以直接追踪
the book with
这本书
that this is about Christ who's our
这是关于基督谁是我们的
Savior Paul is just saturated with the
救主保罗刚满足于
gospel in the book of Ephesians but what
以弗所书中的福音， 但是什么
I want to do is just brainstorm with you
我想做的只是和你一起集体讨论
a little bit what does it mean to be a
一点点是什么意思
gospel saturated home and if I started
如果我开始，福音饱和的家
having you call out words related to the
让你喊出与之相关的词语
gospel it would be really easy to get
得到福音书真的很容易
there we would start saying things like
在那里我们会开始说像
mercy grace forgiveness love
怜悯宽恕爱情
reconciliation those are all wonderful
和解这些都很精彩
gospel saturated words right well when
福音饱和话权以及当
we say gospel a gospel centered home or
我们说福音是一个以福音为中心的福音
a gospel saturated home what should our
一个福音饱和的家，我们应该怎样
homes be like if Christ is the head and
如果基督是头，那就像家一样
we're living out his headship in our
我们在我们的生活中过着头脑
home it's a home where there's grace
在这里，它是一个有恩典的家
it's a home where there's mercy it's a
这是一个有怜悯的家
home where there's reconciliation it's a
家里哪里有和解， 这是一个
home where there's forgiveness granted
获得宽恕的家
undeserved forgiveness granted just as
被视为不值得的宽恕
the Lord does with us and I think that's
主与我们同在，我想是的
what Paul means in Ephesians 6 fathers
保罗在以弗所书6章父亲的意思
don't provoke your children to anger but
不要激怒你的孩子
bring them up in the discipline and
把他们带入纪律和
instruction of the Lord now men what
主现在的 指示是 什么人
that tells me is that we have a
告诉我的是我们有一个
responsibility I have a key
责任我有一把钥匙
responsibility and we looked at this
责任，我们看了这个
last month as we looked at the roles of
上个月 ，因为我们看的角色
men and women and I'll remind you of
男人和女人，我会提醒你的
John Piper's definition of what is
约翰派珀的定义是什么
mature masculinity mature masculinity is
成熟男子气概成熟男子气概
a sense of benevolent so loving
一种如此慈爱的仁慈感
responsibility to lead provide for and
负责领导和提供
protect women or your family in ways
以某种方式保护妇女或家人
appropriate to a man's differing
适合男人的不同
relationships so it's primarily my
关系所以它主要是我的
responsibility to set this type of
设置此类型的责任
pattern this type of tone in my home
在我的家里模仿这种语气
that's a gospel centered tone and a home
这是一个以福音为中心的基调和家庭
that is bringing up my children I have a
那是抚养我的孩子我有一个
little principal in there that has been
在那里小校长已
really important to us notice under the
对我们来说非常重要
phrase bring them up I have in your
这句话把我们带到了你的身上
notes principle and it says that implies
注意原则并且它表示暗示
if I'm bringing
如果我带来的话
my children this is not passive
我的孩子，这不是被动
Parenthood but active Parenthood so
为人父母但积极的父母身份
active Parenthood not passive Parenthood
积极的父母不是被动的父母
and we've preached that to ourselves for
我们已经为自己宣讲了这一点
years this is not about just letting my
多年来这是不是只是让我
children grow up this is about lovingly
孩子长大这是亲切的
giving direction and being involved in
给予指导并参与其中
my children's lives as they're growing
我的孩子们在成长过程中的生活
up active Parenthood not passive
积极的父母不是被动的
Parenthood I mentioned this in the
为人父母我在这里提到过这一点
opening if I am NOT disciple in' either
如果我不是门徒，也要开放
the world or their flesh will something
世界或他们的肉体会有所作为
is going to be bringing them up and if
将要提出来，如果
they're just left to their own flesh
他们只是留给自己的肉体
more about this in the next session
更多关于这一点在下一届会议上
about what is that flesh what's going on
关于什么是肉体正在发生什么
in the heart of a child and proverbs
在一个孩子的心脏和谚语
speaks a lot to that about what's really
关于什么是真的，他 说了很多
going on in the heart of a child a child
在一个孩子的心脏里继续生孩子
will grow up left to it his or her own
会成长为他或她自己
devices how does a child grow up crooked
设备孩子如何长大歪
we need active parents not passive
我们需要积极的父母不被动
parents now even if you don't choose
父母现在即使你不选择
Family Worship as the methodology there
家庭崇拜作为那里的方法
needs to be some type of discipleship
需要成为某种门徒训练
tool that is being used in the life of
正在使用的工具
children this just happens to be the one
孩子这恰好就是那个
that we've chosen I'm gonna wait until
我们选择了我要等到
the next time to talk about the words
下次再谈谈这些话
discipline and instruction since they
他们以来的纪律和指导
fit well with the next session on
与下届会议合身
parental discipline look at the next
父母的纪律看下一个
note point in your notes this is a way
在笔记中注意这是一种方式
for me to fulfill the command to make
让我完成命令
disciples the chief command of the Lord
门徒是主的主要命令
and really another really helpful
而另一个真的很有帮助
principle for me through the years has
多年来我的原则
been this make his last command my first
这是他的第一个命令
concern make his last command our first
关注使他的最后一个命令成为我们
concern what was our Lord's last command
关心我们的主的最后命令是什么
before he ascended to heaven go into all
在他升天之前进入所有人
the world and he didn't say go into all
这个世界，他并没有说全部
the world and tell them about tell them
世界并告诉他们告诉他们
the message about me that's how I used
关于我的消息就是我的用法
to hear it well that's not what it says
很好听，这不是它所说的
it says Matthew 28
它说马太福音28
go into all the world and make disciples
进入所有的世界，使弟子
that which implies there's a message but
这意味着有消息但是
it's much more our children are our
它更加儿童是我们的
chief disciples we're investing in the
我们在投资的首席弟子
lives of our children to make disciples
我们的孩子的生活，使门徒
followers of Jesus Christ out of them so
耶稣基督的信徒 了出来，这样
it's a key way for me to fulfill the
这是我实现这一目标的关键方式
command to make disciples
指挥门徒
now next passage let's go to Deuteronomy
现在下一段让我们去申命记
six then we're gonna get really
六，然后我们会真的
practical with how do you carry out this
实用，你如何实现这一点
family instruction time let me while
家庭指导时间让我同时
you're turning to Deuteronomy 6 I'm
你转向申命记6我
gonna read you another testimony and
会给你读另一个见证和
this one is from our other another son
这一个来自我们另一个儿子
Jonathan John in his wife are about to
乔纳森约翰在他的妻子即将来临
give birth to our second grandchild
生下我们的第二个孙子
we're looking forward to meeting him
我们期待着 与他见面
next month
下个月
Lord willing in about five weeks we get
主愿意在大约五周内得到
to meet grandchild number two and he is
为了满足二号孙子，他是
a church planter the guy you're gonna
一个教堂种植者，你要去的那个人
hear from here is a church planter in
从这里听到的是一位教堂建立者
New Hampshire he and his wife are
他和他的妻子是新罕布什尔州
graduates of the college and the Lord
大学和主的毕业生
has called them to plant a church near
他们叫他们在附近种植一座教堂
Chester New Hampshire here's what John
切斯特新罕布什尔州这里是约翰
had to say about family devotions family
不得不说家庭虔诚的家庭
devotions have helped me in several ways
奉献在很多方面帮助了我
first at a young age it helped me
在年轻的时候， 它帮助了我
recognize the need and delight of
认识到需要和喜悦
spending time in God's Word it also
它也花时间在神的话语中
acted as a daily refocusing of my mind
作为每日重新聚焦我的思想
and heart towards God and away from the
和上帝的心，远离神
distractions of the world second family
分散世界第二大家庭
devotions as implied in the name has
名字中隐含的奉献有
helped our family not only stay close
帮助我们的家人不仅保持亲密
but grow closer over the years as we've
但是我们这些年来越来越接近
gotten older and more busy this
变得越来越老了
closeness established by devotions
奉献建立的亲密关系
helped in the process of moving to
在 搬到 过程中帮助了
California let me put a little
加利福尼亚让我放一点
parentheses in here he wrote this right
括号在这里他写了这个权利
after the Lord transitioned us from
在主转移我们之后
Virginia out here to California and we
弗吉尼亚来到加利福尼亚和我们
left a place where we had lived for 40
离开了我们住了40个地方
years uprooted five of our six children
我们六个孩子中有五个被连根拔起
most of them teenagers at the time and
其中大多数是当时的青少年
moved out here to California so you can
搬出这里加州这样你就可以
imagine it was quite a traumatic
想象一下这是一个非常痛苦的事
experience for our family to uproot them
让我们的家人根除他们的经验
to say goodbye to Fant our friends and
告别Fant我们的朋友和
come here to California so this is very
来到加利福尼亚这是非常好的
reassuring for me to hear his testimony
让我放心听取他的证词
here of how the Lord used devotions
在这里耶和华如何使用虔诚
during that time so he said this
那段时间所以他说了这个
closeness established by devotions
奉献建立的亲密关系
helped the process of moving to
帮助移动的过程
California to be a process of glorifying
加利福尼亚是一个美化的过程
God as a family through the hard times
上帝作为一个家庭度过了艰难时期
that God sovereignly allows and plans
上帝主权允许和计划
devotions tied our family together for
奉献将我们的家人团结在一起
the goal of God's glory then third he
上帝的荣耀的目标然后是他的第三个
says in a more practical way devotions
以更实际的方式表达了奉献精神
have helped me develop the ability to
帮助我发展了自己的能力
lead worship he started at about age 12
领导崇拜他从大约12岁开始
I think third grade he started playing
我认为他开始上三年级
the piano but then about age 12 he
钢琴然后约12岁他
taught himself the guitar and so I just
我自学吉他，所以我只是
turned over music to him during family
在家庭期间将音乐转交给他
devotions and the Lord used that just to
奉献和主使用那只是为了
develop his ability to lead worship and
培养他领导崇拜的能力
he ended up being a worship pastor for a
他最终成为一名崇拜牧师
while he says playing music every day in
而他说每天都在播放音乐
leading worship every day has helped me
每天领导的崇拜都对我有所帮助
grow musically and spiritually and I
在音乐和精神上成长，我
really appreciate John and what the Lord
真的很感谢约翰和主
is doing in his life
在他的生活中
here's another key passage Deuteronomy 6
这是另一个关键段落申命记6
homes that our God saturated home so we
我们的上帝在我们这里饱和的家园
saw in the last point gospel saturated
在最后一点看到福音饱和了
and now God saturated worship should be
现在神饱和的崇拜应该是
the atmosphere of our homes it's the way
我们家的气氛就是这样
we live life we're living as we saw I
我们生活在一起，就像我们看到的那样
think it was last month when we talked
我们认为这是上个月我们谈过的时候
about the heart that life's about
关于生命的内心
worship and we're living as worshipers
崇拜，我们作为崇拜者生活
so Deuteronomy 6 says this verse for the
所以申命记6说这节经文
Shema passage says hear o Israel the
谢马说，听到以色列的话
Lord is our God the Lord is one and you
主是我们的上帝，主与你同在
shall love the Lord your God with all
应当爱主你的 神与所有
your heart and with all your soul and
你的心灵，你的灵魂和灵魂
with all your might and these words
尽你所能和这些话
which I'm commanding you today shall be
我今天要求你的是
on your heart and you shall teach them
在你心中，你将教导他们
diligently to your sons and shall talk
勤勉地对你的儿子们说话
of them when you sit in your house when
他们的，当你 在你的房子时，坐
you walk
你走了
the way when you lie down when you rise
你上升时躺下的方式
up you shall bind them as a sign on your
你应该把它们绑在你的身上
hand and they shall be as frontlets of
他们将成为他们的先锋
your house and on your your gates a God
你的房子和你的大门上帝
saturated home what are we trying to do
饱和的家我们想做什么
pass down to the next generation pass
传递给下一代传球
the baton to the next generation to be
指挥棒到下一代
god-fearers followers of Christ a
敬畏基督的追随者a
worship saturated home terminology I
崇拜饱和的家庭术语我
like to use is this a Theo centric view
喜欢使用这是一个以Theo为中心的观点
of life life is about God we are living
生命就是关于我们生活的上帝
in his world we're living in his
在他的世界里，我们生活在他的世界里
environment and part of counseling
环境和部分咨询
problems is people trying to live
问题是人们试图生活
independent of that we are made to be in
独立的，我们做成的
relationship with God a theá-- centric
与上帝的关系 - 以中心为中心
view of life or a doxological view of
生活观或生理观点
life and here's a quick review for us of
生活，这里是我们的 快速回顾
what we saw some of the other months as
我们看到了其他几个月的情况
we've been together Matthew chapter 6
我们一直在马修第6章
where your treasure is there your heart
你的宝贝在哪里，你的心脏
will be also
也将
what are we valuing what are we
我们在重视什么是我们的
treasuring what is of worth to us and
珍惜是什么值得我们和
then passing down to our children that
然后传递到我们的孩子，
the Lord is of the greatest worth the
主是最有价值的
way that we've chosen to do that in our
我们选择在我们这样做的方式
home is using this methodology of having
家里正在使用这种方法
family worship just to give you a
家庭崇拜只是为了给你一个
practical idea of how often we do this
我们经常这样做的实际想法
this is not everyday this is probably 5
这不是每天这可能是5
out of 7 days a week and through the
出每周7天，并通过
years we've changed the time depending
多年来我们改变了时间
on the needs of our family most often
最常见的是我们家庭 的需求
it's been before bedtime
它是在睡觉前
10 to 20 minutes before bedtime so it's
睡前 10到20分钟所以它是
not overbearing I think you we could
没有霸道我认为你可以
teach people how to find 10 minutes or
教人们如何找到10分钟或
15 minutes of time in their schedule
他们的日程安排有 15 分钟的时间
especially by turning off the television
特别是关掉电视
that'd be a very helpful thing to do and
那会是一件非常有益的事情 ，
spending 15 to 20 minutes we sing
花15到20分钟我们唱歌
together sing a couple of songs right
一起唱几首歌吧
now we're going through proverbs again
现在我们再次经历谚语
together it's probably the fourth or
同时它可能是第四或
fifth time we've been through proverbs
我们第五次通过谚语
through the years and then we pray
多年来，我们祈祷
together and then
一起然后
sometimes finish with another song so
有时完成另一首歌
it's not overwhelming with the amount of
它的数量并不算是压倒性的
time and then I'll be giving you some
时间，然后我会给你一些
practical ideas how to do this in just a
实际的想法如何在一个
moment
时刻
so Wurst worship worth-ship what am i
所以Wurst崇拜值得我发送什么
valuing where your treasure is there
重视宝藏在哪里
your heart will be also and I hate to
你的心也会和我讨厌
put this slide up again but it's just a
把这张幻灯片重新放上，但它只是一个
funny slide and it'll remind you of last
有趣的幻灯片，它会让你想起最后一个
month so there we go
那么我们去吧
what are we worshiping what are we
我们崇拜的是什么呢？
valuing and we were we believe we were
重视并且我们相信我们是
made to be worshipers of the true and
成为真实和真实的崇拜者
living God we're made to be in a
活着的上帝，我们成了一个
relationship with God we want to teach
我们想教导 与神的 关系
our children that the greatest thing in
我们的孩子是最伟大的事情
life is to be in relationship with the
生活就是要与生活息息相关
creator of the universe that is the most
宇宙的创造者是最多的
exciting thing the most fulfilling the
令人兴奋的事情最充实的
most satisfying thing about life is to
关于生命最令人满意的事情是
be in relationship with the Creator Paul
与创造者保罗有关系
was excited about that right Philippians
对那个正确的腓立比人感到很兴奋
3:10 that I may know him and the power
3:10我可以认识他和权力
of his resurrection excited about being
他复活的兴奋是
a follower of Christ that gives me
基督的追随者给了我
another little principle about family
关于家庭的另一个小原则
worship it shouldn't be boring I don't
崇拜它不应该无聊我不
want to teach my children that
我想教给我的孩子们
worshipping God is boring so I'll give
崇拜上帝很无聊所以我会给予
you some ideas about that about how to
你对如何做的 一些想法
keep it focused and exciting and et
保持专注和兴奋等
cetera we're made to be worshippers and
等等我们做成的崇拜者和
we've talked about that in other months
我们在其他几个月里谈过这个问题
so I can go through this pretty quickly
所以我可以很快地完成这个
what that means is I'm trying to make as
这意味着我正在努力做到
you see in your notes there and I'm on
你看到你的笔记，我在
this top of the second page and my notes
这第二页的顶部和我的笔记
that point three it says this makes the
这三点它说这使得
heart the target what are you living for
目标是你的目标
what are you worshiping I want my
你在崇拜什么我想要我的
children to be heart aware I don't want
孩子要心里意识到我不想要
them to be naive about their motives I
他们是天真的有关他们的动机我
don't want them to be a naive about the
不要让他们天真地对待
worshipping nature of the heart more
崇拜自然的心更多
about this the next time how we use
下次我们如何使用这个
discipline to help focus them on their
纪律，以帮助他们专注于他们的
need of the gospel they need to
需要他们需要的福音
understand the sin nature and why they
了解罪的本质及其原因
desperately need a Savior what is the
迫切需要一个救主是什么
heart again the heart is our once drives
再一次，心灵是我们曾经的动力
desires passions yearnings thoughts and
欲望激情渴望思想和
intentions as Hebrews
作为希伯来人的意图
4:12 that's real Christianity is at the
4:12真正的基督教就是这样
level of the heart Matthew 22 says love
心灵的水平马太福音22说爱
the Lord your God with all your heart
耶和华你的上帝全心全意
soul mind and strength I'm gonna just
灵魂思想和力量我只会
speed up here a little bit we covered
这里加快我们介绍一点点
this the last time we want to live as if
这是我们最后一次想要活得好像
everything is from him through him and
一切都是从他通过他和他
to him I don't need to cover that since
对他来说， 我不需要掩饰
we did last month what this leads to is
上个月我们做了什么 ， 这导致是
these type of principles if we're
如果我们这样做，这些原则
creating this kind of atmosphere in our
在我们这里创造这种氛围
homes I think this can happen kids what
家我认为这可能发生在孩子身上
we have in the Lord is so much better it
我们在上帝是如此美好它
makes it a lot easier to say no to the
使得它容易得多说不
world it's still going to be hard
世界它仍然很难
because our flesh is really strong and
因为我们的肉体非常强壮
our desires are strong and the world is
我们的愿望是强大的，世界是
really alluring but can we try to make
真的很诱人，但我们可以尝试制作
the Lord more alluring and more
主更具诱惑力和更多
wonderful and more beautiful so that we
美好而美丽让我们
desire our children to be so satisfied
希望我们的孩子如此满意
in relationship with Christ that the
在与基督的关系中
world does not have the allure that it
世界上还没有的吸引力，它
normally does because we're worshipers
通常是因为我们是崇拜者
were made to be worshipers kids we were
我们被当作崇拜者
made for something bigger why settle for
为更大的东西做了为什么要满足
second best when we're made for
我们做的时候第二好
something really really big you get to
你得到的东西真的很大
be in relationship with the creator of
与...的创造者有关系
the universe a song that we love to sing
宇宙是我们喜欢唱的歌
is this one give me one pure and holy
这是一个给我一个纯洁和圣洁的人
passion we're kind of stuck in a rut we
激情我们那种固守成规，我们
sing this couple of times a week
一周唱这几次
give me one pure and holy passion give
给我一个纯洁和神圣的激情给予
me one magnificent obsession give me one
我一个宏伟的痴迷给了我一个
glorious ambition for my life to know
我生命中要知道的光荣雄心
and follow hard after you to know and
并且在你知道和之后努力追随
follow hard after you to grow as your
在你成长为你的后，努力追随
disciple in the truth this world is
这世界是真理的门徒
empty
空
pale and poor compared to knowing you my
与认识你的相比，脸色苍白， 贫穷
lord lead me on and I will run after you
上帝带领我，我会追你
lead me on and I will run after you last
对领导我，我会在你最后一次 运行
point of building a theology of family
建立家庭神学的观点
worship just as the last argument the
崇拜就像最后一个论点一样
picture of the New Testament church what
新约教会的图片是什么
are we called
我们打电话了吗？
brothers and sisters in Christ and I
基督里和我的兄弟姐妹
think of the family nuclear family as a
把家庭核心家庭想象成一个
picture just a mini picture of the body
图片只是身体的迷你图片
the body of Christ and if the bigger
基督的身体，如果更大
church the local church is called the
教堂当地教堂被称为
worship if the family and it's pictured
崇拜， 如果家庭和它的照片
as a family shouldn't families be
作为一个家庭不应该是家庭
worshiping together so the family is a
一起崇拜所以家庭是一个
mini picture of the New Testament church
新约教会的迷你图片
let's go on to some advantages of family
让我们继续享受家庭的一些优势
worship and think about this for a
崇拜，想想这一个
moment what are some advantages to
此刻都有些什么 优势
family worship it has led to great unity
家庭崇拜它导致了很大的团结
in our family lots of wonderful memories
在我们家里有很多美好的回忆
helping prepare our children for life we
帮助我们的孩子为生活做好准备
want to be the ones to talk to our
想成为与我们交谈的人
children about homosexuality we want to
孩子们关于我们想要的同性恋
be the ones to talk to our children
成为与我们的孩子交谈的人
about abortion we want to be the ones
关于我们希望成为堕胎的人
that talk to our children about tsunamis
这些传言对我们的孩子约海啸
and how can a loving God use a storm a
和慈爱的上帝 怎么能用 一个风暴
tsunami that killed hundreds of
海啸造成数百人死亡
thousands of people we want to be the
我们想成为成千上万的人
ones that talk to our children about
那些与我们的孩子谈论的事情
those things right helping prepare our
那些正确帮助我们准备的事情
children for life what a great time to
孩子们的生活是多么美好的时光
have family meetings that's just been
举行过刚开始的家庭聚会
natural for us if there's something our
如果我们有什么东西，对我们来说很自然
family has had to gather and meet and
一家人不得不聚集和见面
talk about family worship time is just
谈论家庭崇拜时间是公正的
the natural time for us to have a family
我们拥有一个家庭的自然时间
meeting
会议
so it helps communication we are
所以有助于沟通我们
notorious for getting off on what we
因为我们的下落而臭名昭着
call bunny trails so we start doing
叫兔子小径，所以我们开始做
prayer requests and somebody starts the
祈祷请求和某人开始
prayer request leads into a story about
祈祷请求引导到一个故事
the day and then after five minutes I
一天，然后五分钟后我
have to say I'm sorry I let us get off
不得不说我很抱歉我让我们下车
on another bunny trail let's get this
在另一条兔子小径上让我们来看看
refocused again it's a time for us just
重新聚焦这是我们的时间
to laugh and talk about the day conflict
笑，谈论当天的冲突
resolution natural time to deal with
分辨率自然时间来处理
issues it has led to stability
这导致了稳定的问题
we've lived we have led a extremely full
我们生活过得非常充实
life of over 30 years in full-time
全职生活超过30年
ministry and we were determined early on
事工和我们很早就确定了
that we needed things in our lives that
我们生活中需要的东西
would help stabilize our family in the
将有助于稳定我们的家庭
midst of all the busyness and the chaos
所有的忙碌和混乱中
that menaced full-time ministry can
威胁全职事工的人可以
cause what are you gonna do to keep your
因为你要做什么来保持你的
family stable and this was one of the
家庭稳定，这是的一个
things that was just we could count on
的事情，只是我们能指望
we were gonna have this time together to
我们一起度过这段时间
talk and pray and sing it's been a great
说话， 祈祷，唱歌，这是一个伟大的
way to teach the guys in our family how
教我们家里人怎么样的方法
to be leaders and turn over leadership
成为领导者并领导领导
to them one of the most gratifying
最令人欣慰的给他们一个
memories I have is when Rose and I were
我有的回忆就是罗斯和我
in Australia a few years ago and
在澳大利亚，几年前和
normally I would say to one of the guys
通常我会对其中一个人说
okay well I'm going you need to make
好吧，我要去做你需要做的
sure you initiate and lead family
确定你发起并领导家庭
worship got to Australia are on the way
到澳大利亚的崇拜正在进行中
to Australia realized I hadn't assigned
到澳大利亚意识到我没有分配
that to anyone and one of the first
对任何人和第一个
things I wanted to talk to them about
我想和他们谈谈的事情
was somebody lead family worship while
有人带领家庭崇拜
I'm going and I said something I think
我要去，我说了一些我想的
it was to Joel and he said we've already
这是乔尔，他说我们已经
done that and that was just very
做到这一点，那就是只是很
reassuring for me that they were so
让我放心，他们是如此
concerned about this that they took the
关心这一点，他们采取了
initiative themselves even while we were
即使在我们的时候也会主动
gone we've created lots of memories
走了，我们创造了很多回忆
we've had Muslims in our home during
我们家里有穆斯林
family worship all kinds of wonderful
家庭崇拜各种精彩
memories one time we had missionaries
记忆有一次我们有传教士
from Europe visiting with us and you
来自欧洲与我们和你一起访问
know the typical Europeans they can
知道他们能做 的典型欧洲人
speak five languages so we had
说五种语言， 所以我们有
missionaries in our home and they had
在我们家里的传教士， 他们有
their children and they had two
他们的孩子和他们有两个
teenagers from Europe with them so we
来自欧洲的青少年和我们在一起
had five different languages they knew
有五种 他们认识的不同语言
the same praise songs that we did and we
我们和我们一样赞美歌曲
had two different guitars going so as we
我们有两把不同的吉他
were singing the praise songs we
正在唱赞歌我们
normally sing they sang them in four
通常唱歌，他们唱四个
different languages while we sang in
我们唱歌的时候有不同的语言
English so we had five languages going
英语， 所以我们有五种语言
at the same time just a little picture
同时只是一张小图片
of Revelation chapter five of people
启示录第五章的人
from every tongue and tribe and nation
来自各个舌头，部落和国家
we
我们
shipping the Lord that's one of our
运送主，这是我们的一个
favorite memories and we have lots of
最喜欢的回忆，我们有很多
fun we've acted out skits together of
有趣的是，我们一起表演了短剧
course
课程
Noah and the flood and the Christmas
诺亚和洪水和圣诞节
story and we get out our beanie babies
故事，我们走出我们的豆豆宝宝
and you know all the little things to
你知道所有的小事情
have the animals to fill the ark all
有动物所有填写方舟
kinds of things just lots of memories
各种各样的事情只是很多回忆
lots of different creative things that
很多不同的创意事物
you can do now here's some suggestions
你现在可以做这里的一些建议
for carrying out family worship and
进行家庭崇拜和
using it as a method to disciple and
用它作为门徒和门徒的方法
instruct your children let me emphasize
指导你的孩子让我强调
again if you don't the command of
再次，如果你不指挥
Scripture is for children or for parents
圣经适合儿童或父母
to disciple their children if you don't
如果你不这样做，就要训练他们的孩子
use family worship you have to come up
使用家庭崇拜你必须上来
with some type of methodology because
用某种方法，因为
the idea of parents disciple their
父母的想法是他们的门徒
children is a clear instruction of
儿童是一个明确的指示
Scripture number one John 17 in John 8
约翰福音8章中的第一个约翰福音17章
John 17:17 says the law in the Lord
约翰福音17:17说在主里面的律法
praying there he said sanctify them
在那里祈祷他说要使他们成圣
through your truth your word is truth
通过你的真相，你的话就是真理
the Word of God needs to be central the
上帝的话语需要成为中心
Word of God needs to be central you're
上帝的话语需要成为你的核心
not hearing me say that we read
没有听到我说我们读过
scripture every night we if we're in a
每天晚上我们如果我们在一个经文中
hurry
匆忙
maybe we're rushing because we all got
也许我们匆匆忙忙，因为我们都得到了
home late we at least pray together but
回家晚我们至少一起祈祷但是
the Word of God needs to be a key
上帝的话语需要成为关键
component in this family worship time or
这个家庭中的组成部分崇拜时间或
any discipleship time John 8:32 says you
任何门徒时间约翰福音8:32说你
will know the truth and the truth will
会知道真相和真相
set you free so the Word of God needs to
让你自由，所以神的话语需要
be central to parental discipleship of
是父母的门徒训练的核心
children music I've been trying to
儿童音乐我一直在努力
convince my son John the musician that
说服我的儿子约翰这位音乐家
for non musical families somebody needs
对于非音乐家庭，有人需要
to do an accompaniment DVD or something
做伴奏DVD或其他什么
you do some hymns or do something that
你做一些赞美诗或做一些事情，
families that don't have pianists and
家庭没有钢琴家和
musicians that you could still sing
你仍然可以唱歌的音乐家
along and do some music for a long time
和长时间做一些音乐
we have another guitarist now but for a
我们现在有另一位吉他手但是为了一个
long time we just sang out acapella
很长一段时间我们只唱出了acapella
remember scripture says make a joyful
记得圣经说要快乐
noise to the Lord so even if it's just a
对主的喧哗，即使它只是一个
noise enjoy singing and
噪音喜欢唱歌和
worshiping to the Lord prayer is
崇拜主祈祷是
obviously central we've done a lot of
显然我们做了很多工作
reading together one of our traditions
一起阅读我们的传统之一
at Christmas we've done this for years
在圣诞节我们已经做了多年
and years is reading John Piper's little
和几年正在读约翰·派博的小
book seeing and savoring Jesus Christ we
我们看到和品味耶稣基督
do that almost every December read
这几乎每年12月都会这样做
through that book together since that's
从那以后一起通过那本书
what Christmas is about savoring our
圣诞节是关于品尝我们的
savior whatever current topics another
救世主当前的话题另一个
book that we've read through a couple of
我们读过几本书
times as pilgrims progress and you can
倍朝圣者的进步，你可以
get it in modern English you don't have
用你没有的现代英语得到它
to read it in the Old English so I would
用古英语阅读它，所以我愿意
highly recommend pilgrims progress and
强烈推荐朝圣者的进步和
it's the version we have has discussion
这是我们讨论过的版本
questions with it and that's been really
对它的问题，这是真的
helpful for our children current topics
有助于我们的孩子当前的主题
and issues tsunamis homosexuality
并发布海啸同性恋
abortion we talk about all those things
堕胎我们谈论所有这些事情
with our children theology we've gone
与我们的孩子神学，我们走了
through catechisms with our kids
通过我们孩子的教理问答
whatever a family need is like conflict
无论家庭需要什么都像冲突
resolution dealing with conflicts one of
处理冲突的决议之一
the books we read was peacemaking for
我们读的书是为了和平
families we just did that within the
家庭我们刚刚做的是中
last year so that we were teaching our
去年，我们正在教我们的
kids some basic biblical conflict
孩子们一些基本的圣经冲突
resolution principles as I mentioned
我提到的决议原则
we've done skits together missions and
我们一起做了短剧任务和
evangelism let me give you some ideas
传福音让我给你一些想法
here we haven't been doing this in
在这里，我们还没有这样做
recent years but for a long time you
最近几年，但很长一段时间你
know those prayer cards that you get
知道你得到的那些祷告卡
from missionaries and you wonder what in
从传教士那里你想知道什么
the world do we do with these prayer
这个世界我们做这些祷告
cards my refrigerator only holds a
卡我的冰箱只有一个
certain amount of prayer cards so what
一定数量的祷告卡是什么
do you do with all those prayer cards of
你跟所有的那些祷告卡做
missionaries we had a box and we'll you
传教士，我们有一个盒子，我们会
just kept all the prayer cards in a box
把所有的祷告卡都放在一个盒子里
of our missionaries and then eventually
我们的传教士然后最终
it had turned into when people sent us
当人们发送给我们时，它已经变成了
pictures at Christmas we put those of
在圣诞节我们把那些照片
our friends and family we put those in
我们的朋友和家人，我们把这些
that box and each day we would just
那个盒子和我们每天都会
whichever one was at the front we would
无论哪一个在前面，我们都会
pull out that missionary picture or that
拉出那张传教士的照片
family picture and we would pray for
家庭照片，我们会祈祷
those people and then put it at the back
那些人，然后把它放在后面
of the pile and just keep rotating
堆的，只是保持旋转
through the missionary prayer cards that
通过传教祷告卡
way missions and evangelism I mentioned
我提到的方式使命和传福音
to you that
对你而言
we had we adopted a Muslim student while
我们曾经接过过一名穆斯林学生
we were at Virginia Tech and Abbas
我们在弗吉尼亚理工大学和阿巴斯
Hussein was our adopted Muslim from
侯赛因是我们收养的穆斯林
United Arab Emirates he was a student
阿拉伯联合酋长国他是一名学生
there and he would come to our home he
在那里他会来我们家
knew we were believers and I would say
知道我们是信徒，我会说
to him Abbas we're gonna have Family
对他来说阿巴斯我们要有家人
Worship if you would like to leave we
崇拜，如果你想离开我们
would totally understand but we'd love
会完全明白，但我们会爱
to have you stay if you'd like to stay
如果你想留下来，请你留下来
and he never refused to stay
他从不拒绝留下来
he sat through Family Worship with us
他和我们一起坐在家庭崇拜中
numerous times and we think of him often
无数次，我们经常想起他
and hope that the Lord uses something to
并希望主使用某些东西
penetrate his soul with the gospel as he
用福音传播他的灵魂
saw a Christian family a true Christian
看到基督徒家庭成为真正的基督徒
family interacting with the world and
家庭与世界 互动
enjoying worshiping the Lord Saturday
星期六享受敬拜主
night the reason I have this up here is
晚上我在这里的原因是
because part of my philosophy is that
因为我的哲学的 一部分 是
Sunday morning is extremely important if
星期天早上非常重要
part of our goal as Christians is to be
我们作为基督徒的目标的一部分是要
have our souls deeply satisfied in
让我们的灵魂深深满足
relationship with the Lord
与主的关系
that makes Sunday morning corporate
这使得周日早上成为公司
worship extremely important right that
崇拜极其重要的权利
we should go hungry and thirsty for the
我们应该去又饥又渴的
Lord well I'm gonna have a hard time
主井我要去有一个困难时期
being hungry and thirsty if I didn't
如果我没有，我会感到饥饿和口渴
have a good night's sleep on Saturday
有一个良好的夜间 周六睡眠
night so we tried to get our kids in bed
晚上， 所以我们试着让我们的孩子在床上
at a decent time on Saturday night we
在星期六晚上的一个体面的时间我们
didn't want to stay up super late on
我不想熬夜超级
Saturday night and our worship time on
星期六晚上和我们的崇拜时间
Saturday night was just a little bit
周六晚上只是一点点
longer if normal time was 10 to 15
如果正常时间是10到15，则更长
minutes Saturday night might be 20 to 25
星期六晚上的分钟可能是20到25分钟
minutes and it was all focused on how do
分钟，这一切都集中在如何做
we get ready for Sunday morning worship
我们为周日早上的礼拜做好准备
service and I would usually switch out
服务，我通常会切换出来
of whatever passage I'm normally reading
无论我正在阅读什么段落
or book I'm reading and we would focus
或书我正在阅读，我们会专注
on Psalms and praise psalms just to
诗篇和赞美诗只是为了
start getting our soul focused and ready
开始让我们的灵魂专注并准备好
for Sunday morning we pray for our
星期天早上，我们为我们祈祷
pastor or we would pray for me as the
牧师或者我们会 为我祈祷
pastor when I was pastoring and pray for
牧师，当我牧养和祈祷
the people to come ready to worship etc
人们准备去敬拜等
on Sunday morning
在星期日的早上
there are lots of counseling and
有很多咨询和
discipleship implications of this so let
这种门徒训练意义如此让
me give you some counselling
我给你一些咨询
applications we are worshipers can't get
申请我们是崇拜者无法得到的
around it humans do it every day you're
在它周围，人类每天都会这样做
worshiping something so I want to teach
崇拜的东西，所以我想教
my counsel leaves or the people I'm
我的律师离开了，或者是我的人
disciple
弟子
to live as a worshiper it's one of the
作为崇拜者生活它是其中之一
first tools that I teach men if I'm
我是第一个教我男人的工具
doing marriage counseling or if I'm
做婚姻咨询或如果我
disciple Amman it's one of the first
弟子安曼是第一个
things that I try to get him to do with
我试图让他做的事情
his family is teach him how to lead his
他的家人教他如何领导他的
family in family worship here's how I go
家庭崇拜在这里我是怎么走的
about doing that here's ideally how it
关于做到这一点，理想情况是这样的
would look I tell him about it and my
看起来我告诉他有关它和我的
individual discipleship meeting and then
个别门徒会议然后
maybe he comes or they come the family
也许他来了或他们来到这个家庭
would come and have dinner with you and
会来和你一起吃晚餐 和
watch you lead your family in worship
看着你带领你的家人敬拜
and then you discuss it and then you
然后你讨论它，然后你
tell him next week we're gonna lead
下周告诉他我们要领先
family worship together and then the
一家人一起崇拜然后
following week you're on so he's seen
下周你就开始了，所以他看到了
you lead it you've talked through it
你领导它， 你已经通过它谈过了
with him
和他一起
you've led it together then you watch
你带领它然后你看
him lead it and you're mentoring someone
他领导它，你在指导某人
into leading family worship counseling
进入领导家庭的崇拜辅导
another counseling discipleship
另一个辅导门徒训练
application it encourages male
应用它鼓励男性
leadership and it teaches parents how to
领导和它教导父母如何
disciple children let me finish before I
门徒孩子让我在我之前完成
read Liz's testimony here about family
阅读Liz在这里关于家庭的证词
worship answering some practical
崇拜回答一些实际问题
questions what if a husband's an
如果一个丈夫是一个问题怎么样
unbeliever or will not lead if the
如果不信任或不会领导
husband's an unbeliever
丈夫是一个不信的人
I believe scripture would still call the
我相信经文仍会打电话给
mom-to-be disciple agility ah to be
妈妈将要敏捷啊
appealing to her husband to make sure
呼吁她的丈夫确保
that this is not going to be something
这不会是什么
that he that is going to turn him off to
那将会让他失望的人
the gospel and what if you have a
福音，如果你有一个
husband that will not leave
不会离开的丈夫
again I would urge the wife to appeal to
我再次敦促妻子上诉
the husband let's say he's a believer
丈夫让我说他是一个信徒
he's not leading appeal to the husband
他并没有对丈夫提出上诉
in a godly way to be a spiritual leader
以敬虔的方式成为一个精神领袖
but if he refuses that she should still
但如果他拒绝她仍然应该
lead in family worship because the
因为家庭崇拜而领导
children need to be discipled how do you
孩子们需要被门徒训练你是怎么做的
put this into a busy schedule just like
把这个变成一个繁忙的日程 就像
everything else
其他一切
whatever our priorities get put into our
无论我们的优先事项得到把我们的
schedule so if you're convinced that
如果您确信这一点，请安排好
this is a priority it'll fit you just
这是一个优先事项，它只适合你
make the things you really want to do
做你真正想做的事情
fit into your schedule a couple of
适合你的日程表几个
things we put into our family schedule
我们在家庭日程中加入的东西
because we knew I grew up in a pastor's
因为我们知道我是在牧师中长大的
home and I knew that it was very easy
回家，我知道这很容易
for ministry to cause a family to not be
为了使一个家庭不成为一个部门
close one to a couple of things that we
接近一到两件事情，我们
put into our family schedule right from
直接投入到我们的家庭日程表中
the beginning to keep our family close
开始让我们的家人保持亲密
and I'd urge you to consider these
我恳请你考虑一下这些
because they're getting to be lost arts
因为他们将失去艺术
in our culture that is eating a meal
在我们的文化中吃饭
together we tried to eat a meal together
我们一起努力一起吃了一顿饭
a day evening meal usually was a time
一天晚餐通常是一个时间
that we would gather together and then
我们会聚在一起然后聚在一起
with family worship and those were like
与家人崇拜，那些就像
rocks and our family schedule that we
岩石和我们的家庭安排我们
knew in spite of all the busyness and
尽管所有人都很忙，但我知道
all the all the various directions
所有各方向
everybody was going we're still gonna
每个人都要去，我们还会
have a meal together and we're still
一起吃饭，我们还在
gonna have family worship together and
要去有家庭礼拜在一起，
if you want to talk about the details of
如果你想谈论细节
that see me afterwards because obviously
事后看到我，因为很明显
when you hear kids are teenagers things
当你听到孩子是青少年的事情
start to change when their schedules
他们的日程安排开始改变
start getting inner woven with your
开始与你的内心编织
schedule what if a husband says I don't
安排如果丈夫说我没有
know the Bible very well and I don't
我非常了解圣经，但事实并非如此
know what to say here's what I tell guys
知道该说什么就是我告诉他们的
by a MacArthur Study Bible and I don't
通过麦克阿瑟研究圣经，我没有
get a commission for that by the way and
顺便说得到的佣金是和
just open the Bible to a passage of
只要打开圣经就可以了
Scripture and then skip down to the
经文然后跳到了
study notes and read the study notes and
学习笔记并阅读学习笔记和
discuss it with your family a little bit
和你的家人讨论一下
you don't have to be a brilliant Bible
你不必是一本精彩的圣经
scholar to lead your family in family
学者带领你的家人在家里
worship plus there's lots of material
崇拜加上有很多材料
that's available if you did a search on
如果您进行搜索，则可以使用
family devotional material on Google all
谷歌上所有的家庭奉献材料
kinds of stuff would would show
各种各样的东西会显示出来
let me finish with a daughter's
让我和一个女儿完成
testimony she says this and I this
证词她说这个和我这个
daughter is very quiet and one of the
女儿很安静而且其中之一
things I've appreciated through the
通过我欣赏的东西
years is that even when we have company
即使我们有公司也是如此
and that's one thing we do is if even
这是我们做的一件事，即使是
when we have company we have family
当我们有公司时我们有家人
worship I just tell our company it's
崇拜我只是告诉我们的公司
part of our custom as our family that we
作为我们家人的习惯的一部分，我们
we have a worship time together and
我们在一起有一个崇拜时间
normally what we hear from our company
通常我们从公司听到的
is that they love it they're just really
是他们喜欢它，他们才是真的
happy that they were part of our family
很高兴他们是我们家庭的一部分
our family worship we've had so many
我们的家庭崇拜我们有这么多
people thank us for inviting them so
人民感谢我们，邀请他们如此
don't be intimidated by having a having
不 具有具有被吓倒
company at your home just keep your
在你家里的公司只保留你的
normal family routines and even though
正常的家庭惯例，即使
liz is quiet when we have family worship
当我们有家庭崇拜时，利兹很安静
she still prays and that's always been a
她仍然祈祷，这一直是一个
huge blessing to my heart she says this
我这么说，心里充满了祝福
I look forward to family devotions each
我期待每个家庭的奉献
evening sometimes we'll read different
晚上有时我们会读不同的
devotional books or read through
灵修书籍或通读
different books in the Bible having
圣经中有不同的书籍
devotions really helps me to grow in my
奉献真的帮助我成长
relationship with Christ it makes me
它与基督的关系使我受益
think about the verses we're reading it
想想我们正在读它的经文
if I don't understand something my
如果我不明白我的意思
family is there to help me they help me
家人在那里帮助我他们帮助我
family devotions also help me to be
家庭的奉献也帮助我
closer friends with my family we talk
和我的家人交朋友， 我们谈谈
sing songs and then we pray together
唱歌然后我们一起祈祷
you
您